teachingideas.co.uk 2018-10-02

# Privacy Policy And Terms Of Use | Teaching Ideas

## Introduction:

This Privacy Policy relates to Teaching Ideas, a website which shares lesson ideas and educational resources, at www.www.teachingideas.co.uk. It sets out how the site uses and protects any information that you give when you use this website.

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of users of Teaching Ideas. We encourage all users to act responsibly and with care when it comes to their personal information and that of others. Please read the following Privacy Policy to understand how the information you provide to us is used and protected. If you have any queries or concerns regarding these practices, please [get in touch](mailto:mark@teachingideas.com).

Please note that by visiting and using the Teaching Ideas site, you are agreeing to the use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Changes:

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page occasionally to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy was last updated in May 2016.

**The information that we collect and how we use it** :

The Teaching Ideas site does not collect any personal information from visitors who visit the site, read the ideas or download resources. However, visitors may share their personal information by interacting with the site in other ways:

  * **Mailing List**  \- Visitors to Teaching Ideas can register to receive a free email newsletter, which is managed by [ymlp.com](http://www.ymlp.com/). All personal information provided when registering for our mailing list is saved in YMLP's database. Teaching Ideas sends email newsletters to registered users and personal information (including names and email addresses) is only used to send out these emails. No personal information is sold or shared with others. You can subscribe and unsubscribe from the Teaching Ideas Update mailing list [here](http://www.www.teachingideas.co.uk/mailinglist.htm). You can also read YMLP's [Privacy Policy](http://www.yourmailinglistprovider.com/privacy_policy.html) and [Anti-Spam Policy](http://www.yourmailinglistprovider.com/antispam_policy.html).
  * **Email Contributions  / Feedback Forms **\- We encourage teachers to share their lesson ideas, resources and comments with Teaching Ideas. Any contributions / feedback sent to Teaching Ideas[ via email](mailto:mark@teachingideas.com) will be saved and archived in a Google Mail account (see [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html)). Contributions sent [via our form](https://www.teachingideas.co.uk/share) will also be saved in our site's database, reviewed and then shared with the public on the site, if we feel that they are appropriate. Contributors will receive email from us in relation to their contribution but emails will not be sent for any other reason. Email will be saved in case we need to contact you about your contribution again in the future. If your contribution is used on Teaching Ideas, your name will be published alongside it, unless you tell us that you would not like this information to be published.

## The information that others collect:

Teaching Ideas uses a number of third party services to provide additional functionality to the site and its users. These services may use cookies. Find out more about cookies on our [cookies page](https://www.teachingideas.co.uk/cookies). The third party services used on Teaching Ideas are:

  * **Google Analytics**  \- Teaching Ideas uses Google Analytics to track and monitor statistics about visitors to the site. We use this information, in combination with analytics information from other users, so that it cannot reasonably be used to identify any particular individual user. You can read the [Google Analytics Privacy Overview here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html). To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, Google provide [this browser add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) which you can install on your computers.
  * **Advertisers**  \- In order to provide free lesson ideas and educational resources, Teaching Ideas shows advertising, which are provided by the following services: 
    * Google Adsense and DFP - Read Google's Privacy information and opt out of targeted advertising [here](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).
    * Amazon.co.uk Affiliates - Read Amazon.co.uk's Privacy Notice [here](http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=502584).
    * Criteo - Read Criteo's Privacy Policy [here](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/).
    * Sovrn - Read Sovrn's Privacy Policy [here](http://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/).
    * BuySell Ads - Read BuySell Ads' Privacy Policy [here](https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacy).
  * **RSS / Email subscriptions**  \- Visitors may subscribe to the site (for free) and receive information about the latest additions to Teaching Ideas by RSS and / or email. This service is provided by Google Feedburner. Find out more about Google's privacy principles at the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy/).
  * **Social Media**  \- Teaching Ideas uses a number of social networks to share ideas / information and to promote our resources. Each of these networks have their own privacy policies (i.e. [Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy), [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php), [Google+](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/), [Pinterest](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388) and [LinkedIn](http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy)).
  * **Embedded resources**  \- A number of the resources on Teaching Ideas may be embedded, with permission, from other third party services. Each of these services have their own privacy policies (i.e.[Google Docs](http://www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html), [Youtube](http://www.youtube.com/t/privacy), [Vimeo](http://vimeo.com/privacy) and [Slideshare](http://www.slideshare.net/privacy)).

## Links to other websites:

Teaching Ideas contains links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our sites, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling your personal information:

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please contact [mark@teachingideas.com](mailto:mark@teachingideas.com).

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us as soon as possible, at the above email address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

* * *

## Terms of Use

If you browse and use this website you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following terms and conditions of use, which together with our privacy policy govern Teaching Ideas' relationship with you in relation to this website.

The term "Teaching Ideas" or "us" or "we" refers to the owner of this website, Teaching Ideas Limited. The term "you" refers to the user or viewer of our website.

The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use:

  * The content of the Teaching Ideas site is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.
  * Neither we nor any third parties provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or suitability of the information and materials found or offered on the website for any particular purpose. You acknowledge that such information and materials may contain inaccuracies or errors and we expressly exclude liability for any such inaccuracies or errors to the fullest extent permitted by law.
  * Your use of any information or materials on Teaching Ideas is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable. It shall be your own responsibility to ensure that any products, services or information available through the website meet your specific requirements. Those using our materials are encouraged to check their suitability for use with their students carefully.
  * Teaching Ideas contains material which is owned by or licensed to us, and material which has been freely submitted by third parties. This material includes, but is not limited to, the ideas, activities, resources, design, layout, look, appearance and graphics. Ideas and resources may be freely used by teachers in their own classrooms. Other forms of reproduction are prohibited, without written permission from Teaching Ideas.
  * Unauthorised use of this website and the ideas / resources posted on it may give rise to a claim for damages and/or be a criminal offence.
  * Teaching Ideas also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s).
  * Your use of Teaching Ideas and any dispute arising out of such use of the website is subject to the laws of England and Wales.

Interaction with the site:

  * Some parts of Teaching Ideas allow you to interact, by posting comments and messages. By using these parts, you agree that the information you enter will be posted online and may be immediately visible to others. All comments / messages may be subject to moderation and may be deleted without notice.
  * If you notice any comments which you feel are inappropriate / potentially offensive, please contact mark@teachingideas.com and these will be reviewed as soon as possible.
  * Users who submit ideas / resources for addition to Teaching Ideas should ensure that their contributions are entirely their own work, and must not infringe the copyright of others. By submitting ideas / resources, you grant us free of charge permission to use (and modify where necessary) the material and distribute it to others via the website.

## Disclaimer:

The information contained in this website is for general information purposes only. The information is provided by Teaching Ideas and whilst we endeavour to keep the information up-to-date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.

In no event will we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website.

Through this website you are able to link to other websites which are not under the control of Teaching Ideas. We have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites. The inclusion of any links does not necessarily imply a recommendation or endorse the views expressed within them.

Every effort is made to keep the website up and running smoothly. However, Teaching Ideas takes no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control.
